JOHN ADEYEMO

ajohnofficial2020@gmail.com || <u>www.johnadeyemo.com</u> P.O. Box 5611, Totoro, Abeokuta|| +2349060894766 || LinkedIn

ABOUT ME

A young front end developer, is passionate about STEM development and application in undeserved communities in West Africa, cuttingedge research intersecting between computer science, Robotics and Agriculture, software development and commitment to building a nation worth to be called my nation.

SKILLS

- Front end Development Graphics Design
- JavaScript
- HTML5/CSS3
- Git/GitHub
- Bootstrap 5
- Sass
- Web Hosting
- Team Player
- Overseeing
- Driving

- Corel Draw
- Video editing
- -Leadership
- Social Media
- Management - Yam Plantation
- Cassava Plantation
- Maize Plantation

AWARDS/HONORS

- Recipient, Google Africa Developer Scholarship, Mobile Web Specialist Track, 2021
- 3rd Runner Up_Regional Best, SG Holdings Quiz Competition 2020-2021
- Best Graduating Student, Class of 2020
- Award of Recognition, Highest in UTME 2020 at Ideal Comprehensive College and DLBC Regional Youth Church 2020
- Second Runner up, Sacred Heart Catholic College Literary and Debating Day, Quiz Competition 2020
- Top 20 finalist, Abayomi Oluwatosin Jiboku Foundation Chemistry Competition(AOJFCC 2019)
- Winner, Sacred Heart Catholic College Literary and Debating Day, Quiz Competition 2019
- Winner, World AIDS Day, Quiz Competition 2019

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

- English: Full Working Proficiency
- Yoruba: Native or bilingual Proficiency
- German: Elementary proficiency

EDUCATION

2014 - November 2020 Ideal Comprehensive College, Ogun, NG

- Unified Tertiary Matriculation Examination- 313/400 Top 1%
- Duolingo English Test- 115/160
- West African Senior School Certificate Examination- 2As, 5Bs, 2Cs
- - Class Rank- 1/110
- Valedictorian Class of 2020
- Separate Awards for overall Best in Further Mathematics, Biology, Technical Drawing
- Courses Taken
 - Introduction to Calculus Coursera | University of Sydney
 - Introduction to HTML5 Coursera||University of Michigan
 - Introduction to CSS3 Coursera | | University of Michigan
 - HTML, CSS and JavaScript for Web Developers Coursera | | John **Hopkins University**

WORK EXPERIENCE/INTERNSHIP

April - September 2021 Intern, Computer-ICE Africa

- Received professional tutoring on kick-starting my coding career and I was able to give back to my immediate community by hosting a webinar and providing resources for my peers who are interested in starting their career in software development but really don't know where to start from.
- Worked as the Marketing executive and social media manager to enhance the company's software sale and reaching a larger audience.

3 weeks Volunteer Summer Instructor, Deeper Life Leadership and Entrepreneurship School (DLES 2021)

- Taught senior secondary school students important mathematical concepts to reinforce their understanding of the concepts.
- Coordinated students during various activities and ensured smooth running of the summer program.

COMMUNITY SERVICE

SMAT Ambassador | Deeper Life Bible Church

- Zonal representative, worked with divers group of young people on increasing the social media audience by 25% +
- Give feedbacks on progress at the regional level. 2hrs/week

Student Tutor

- Recommended by teachers to my peers who experienced difficulties in mathematics and the sciences.
- Created WhatsApp group during the pandemic to help my peers catch up on difficult topics. 3hrs/week

EXTRACURRICULARS

2019 - 2020 President/Co-founder | Quiz Club

- Taught peers and prepared Juniors for quiz competitions
- Won several awards and gained recognition for my school as one of the top 6 schools in my state

2017 - 2019 Team leader | JETS Club

- Designed a fruit cell with my teammates using lime juice as the electrolyte (Works on principle of Voltaic cell)
- Extracted alkanoates from natural products to make a perfume with my team (final product failed due to lack of distillation tower in my school laboratory)

2015 -2019 Assistant Captain| Soccer Team

2019 - 2020 Senior Prefect/Headboy

- Coordinated 600+ students on assembly field to ensure serenity
- Initiated infrastructure development during my tenure as the senior prefect
- Co-host, Revamping the Nigerian Economy by Learning and Implementing the Asian Tigers Developmental Strategies-Welcomed students from neighbouring schools to deliberate on successful strategies to move our country forward

6 weeks Team Innovate | Minerva Challenge 2020

 Worked with teammate during the pandemic on creating a sustainable educational model with the reality of virtual learning; Discussed and deliberated via Google Meets and WhatsApp.

2016 - present

Farm Assistant | Family Responsibility

- Worked with siblings and my dad on crop plantation exclusively for family consumption, spanning land clearing, planting, and post planting activities
- Experienced in Yam, Cassava and Maize plantation 8hrs/ week during school time, 30hrs/week during school breaks